netvibesbusiness.com 2019-12-17

# Netvibes | Privacy Policy

Dassault Systèmes SE, a French corporate entity registered in the registry of commerce of Paris, located 10 rue Marcel Dassault, 78140 Vélizy-Villacoublay, FRANCE, (hereinafter “Dassault Systèmes”) processes Personal Data (as defined below) in the course of its business, including the Personal Data of people using and browsing the [http://www.netvibes.com](http://www.netvibes.com/) website (the "Site").

The purpose of this “Privacy Policy” is to inform all individuals from whom Personal Data is collected by Dassault Systèmes ("You" or "Your") how Dassault Systèmes collects and uses such Personal Data and how You can control its use.

**I. Scope of this privacy policy**

This Privacy Policy sets forth the principles and guidelines governing the protection of Your Personal Data (as defined below) including the Personal Data collected on or through the Site.

Dassault Systèmes collects Personal Data either online (including via email) or offline and this Privacy Policy is applicable regardless of the means of collection or processing.

Personal data ("Personal Data") means any information relating to an identified or identifiable person. An identifiable person is a person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to the person.

Non-Personal Data means any information that does not result in the identification of a person.

For visitors and users of the Site, the Sites Terms of Services are incorporated into this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Site and any Personal Data You provide on the Site are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and those Terms of Services.

**II. Data collected**

Personal Data below likely includes:

  *  title
  *  first and last name
  *  postal address
  *  email address
  *  telephone number(s)
  *  login and password
  * type of organization (company, school, university, etc.), organization name, organization size, department and job title;
  * people to whom purchases are shipped;
  * financial data (credit card number and expiry date, name and address of the cardholder);
  * IP address;
  * Cookies (as described in section 10); and
  * any other Personal Data as may be relevant for the purposes listed below.

In all cases, however, the Personal Data gathered is limited to data necessary for the purposes described in Article 4 below.

For visitors and users of the Site: In order to use certain functions and features of the Site, Dassault Systèmes requires that You provide certain Personal Data when visiting or using the Site. You are free to decide whether or not to provide all or part of Your Personal Data. However, if You choose not to provide all or part of this Personal Data, the purposes as described in Article 4 hereafter might not be achieved or not properly achieved, some areas and functions of the Site may not function properly and/or You may be refused access to certain pages on the Site. In particular, You will not be authorized to purchase other services via the Site.

**III. Protection of personal data concerning children**

Dassault Systèmes services are not designed to be marketed to children who are considered as minor under the applicable data protection law and Dassault Systèmes does not knowingly collect or store Personal Data from children under such age.  For children whose usual place of residence is in the European Union, Lichtenstein, Norway or Iceland, the default age at which a person is no longer considered a child is 16 subject to local law to adjust that limit between 13 and 16.

Certain Dassault Systèmes services may be appropriate for use by children, however, in which case children below the age of consent under local data protection laws must seek consent from their parents or guardians prior to creating a Netvibes account or registering a product. Teachers and school administrators may act in the place of parents and guardians and provide consent for the collection of Personal Data from children (schools should always ensure that they have received permission from parents or guardians to do so).

If parents or guardians become aware that their child has provided Dassault Systèmes with Personal Data without their consent or without a teacher’s or school administrator’s consent, they can ask Dassault Systèmes to remove such Personal Data and terminate the child’s account by sending a request at <http://www.netvibes.com/en/contact-us>.

If Dassault Systèmes becomes aware that it has collected Personal Data from a child below the age of consent under local data protection laws without consent from a parent or guardian, Dassault Systèmes will take steps to seek the parents or guardians consent for that processing or to remove such Personal Data and terminate the child’s account.

**IV. Purposes and legal grounds for processing personal data**

Dassault Systèmes collects Your Personal Data for the following legal grounds and for the following purposes:

  * Processing activities based on Your consent: 
    * To recognize that You have given a Personal Data so you don't need to do it for every web page requested;
    * To enable You to request and receive information on Dassault Systèmes and Dassault Systèmes’ products and services from Dassault Systèmes or a third party engaged by Dassault Systèmes;
    * To ascertain Your requirements and interests and provide You with the most suitable products and/or services ;
    * To enable Dassault Systèmes to manage its marketing activities;
    * To enable You to enter a contest;

Dassault Systèmes may provide a hashed user ID to third party operated social networks or other web offerings (such as Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, Instagram, or Google) where this information is matched against the social networks’ data own data bases in order to display to You more relevant information.

  * Processing activities based on Dassault Systèmes’ legitimate interest: 
    * To improve Your user experience;
    * To enable Dassault Systèmes to manage surveys;
    * To enable Dassault Systèmes to manage its marketing activities for similar goods and products if You are already using Dassault Systèmes’ products and services;
    * To manage the Dassault Systèmes obligations related to applicable export laws, trade sanctions, and embargoes issued, without limitation, by the European Union and its member states, and of the United States of America. This may include (i) automated checks of any user registration data as set out herein and other information You provide about Your identity against applicable sanctioned-party lists; (ii) regular repetition of such checks whenever a sanctioned-party list is updated or when You update Your information; (iii) blocking of access to Dassault Systèmes services and systems in case of a potential match; and (iv) contacting You to confirm Your her identity in case of a potential match;.
  * Processing activities based on the performance of a contract : 
    * To enable You to register, create and maintain an account in order to obtain the services accessible from the Site, specialized documentation and technical assistance.
    * To provide You with a personalized interactive use of the Site
    * To access all the features and options offered by the Site;
    * To enable You to display personal information about You , including Your name and avatar and to exchange with other users of the Site;
    * To enable Dassault Systèmes to manage its business relationships, including sales opportunities, commercial offers, purchasing, contracts, orders, invoices, which may include conversational data triggered via chat functionalities on the Site, contact forms, emails, and voice messaging data; and
    * To provide You with commercial or support-type services.

Generally, when consent is not required, You cannot opt out of non-marketing related communications that are required for the relevant business relationship. With regard to marketing-related communications (e.g., emails and phone calls), Dassault Systèmes will (i) where legally required, only send You such communications after you have opted in, and (ii) provide You the opportunity to opt out of receiving further marketing-related communications from Dassault Systèmes.

Subject to applicable local law, by providing Personal Data such as but not limited to e-mail address, You hereby expressly authorize, Dassault Systèmes, which is part of a global group, and its affiliates (“3DS Group Companies”) to use it together with other relevant Personal Data to send You commercial or marketing communications.

Dassault Systèmes might also use Your email address for administrative or other non-marketing purposes (for example, to notify You of significant changes to the Site or , the non-compliance with the Terms of Use of the Site or a social media made available through that Site where Dassault Systèmes becomes aware of such non-compliance).

**V. Personal data retention period**

Dassault Systèmes does not store Your Personal Data for more time than necessary. Retention periods may vary depending on the data categories and the processing activities.

Where Dassault Systèmes is processing and using Your Personal Data as permitted by law or under your consent, Dassault Systèmes will store Your Personal Data (i) only as long as required to fulfill the purposes set out above, (ii) until You object to Dassault Systèmes’ use of your Personal Data (where Dassault Systèmes has a legitimate interest in using Your Personal Data), or (iii) where you gave Your consent, until you withdraw it. However, where Dassault Systèmes is required by applicable law to retain your Personal Data longer or where Your Personal Data is required to assert or defend against legal claims, Dassault Systèmes will retain Your Personal Data until the end of the relevant retention period or until the claims in question have been settled.

Detailed information related to the different retention is available at <http://faq.netvibes.com/knowledgebase/articles/1858447-personal-data-retention-period>

**VI. Transfer of personal data**

If You are accessing the Site from a location outside of the European Union, with laws or regulations governing data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from those of the European Union, please note that through Your continued use of the Site, which is governed by French law, the corresponding Terms of Services and this Privacy Policy, You are transferring Your Personal Data to the European Union and You consent to that transfer.

As a member of a global group, Dassault Systèmes is able to use available technology to efficiently manage Personal Data and obtain such Personal Data online or otherwise throughout its affiliates’ international operations.  Personal Data may be collected through the Site and subsequently disclosed to and used by a 3DS Group Company for the purposes stated in article 4 of this Privacy Policy.

Please note that Dassault Systèmes may transfer Your Personal Data outside of the European Union, as long as before transferring Your Personal Data, Dassault Systèmes has ascertained that non-European Union entities, including 3DS Group Companies, offer an adequate level of protection in accordance with European legislation. 3DS Group Companies’ location is available at <https://www.3ds.com/about-3ds/world-presence/>.

**VII. Right to access, to rectification and other rights**

Dassault Systèmes will take reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Data collected is used for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy and that such Personal Data is correct and up to date.

If You have an account, You have a right to access Your Personal Data. In addition, You have a right to request the rectification, completion, update or erasure of Your Personal Data by logging on to Your account. You have a right to restrict processing. You also have a right to obtain a copy of Your Personal Data stored by Dassault Systèmes. You have a right to object, in relation to specific processing of Your Personal Data. Additionally, You may have a right to data portability. Otherwise, You may exercise Your rights by sending a request at <http://www.netvibes.com/en/contact-us>

Depending on the scope of the request, Dassault Systèmes reserves the right to charge a reasonable fee to cover any out-of-pocket costs incurred in connection with such access, modification and deletion of Personal Data.  Dassault Systèmes may deny access to Personal Data in limited circumstances, defined by applicable laws and regulations.

**VIII. Data recipients**

Your Personal Data may be disclosed to and used by a 3DS Group Company for the purposes stated in Article 4 of this Privacy Policy.

Where Dassault Systèmes has knowledge that a third party to which Dassault Systèmes has provided Personal Data for the purposes listed in Article 4 above, is using or disclosing Personal Data contrary to this Privacy Policy or to applicable laws, Dassault Systèmes will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop such use or disclosure. Dassault Systèmes will also disclose Personal Data to third parties if Dassault Systèmes determines that such disclosure is necessary for technical reasons (such as hosting services by a third party) or to protect Dassault Systèmes’ legal interests (such as in the event of sale of assets to a third company, or change of control or total or partial liquidation of Dassault Systèmes).

Dassault Systèmes may also disclose Your Personal Data if required by law or if Dassault Systèmes believes in good faith that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (for example, a warrant, a subpoena, or other court order) or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Dassault Systèmes, our customers, or the public.

If allowed by applicable law, Dassault Systèmes may also share Your Personal Data with third parties in order to offer You targeted marketing or advertising.

**IX. Data security**

Dassault Systèmes undertakes to ensure the protection and security of Personal Data that You choose to communicate, in order to ensure the confidentiality of Your Personal Data and prevent Your Personal Data from being distorted, damaged, destroyed or disclosed to unauthorized parties.

Dassault Systèmes maintains reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. As part of those safeguards, Dassault Systèmes employs sophisticated technology designed to protect Personal Data during its transmission and prevent transmission errors or unauthorized acts of third parties. However, while Dassault Systèmes strives to protect Your Personal Data, in light of the inevitable risks of data transmission over the internet, Dassault Systèmes cannot guarantee full protection against any error occurring during the course of Personal Data transmission, which is beyond Dassault Systèmes' reasonable control.

Since all Personal Data is confidential, access is limited to employees, contractors and agents of 3DS Group Companies who have a need to know such data in carrying out their tasks. All the people who have access to Your Personal Data are bound by a duty of confidentiality and subject to disciplinary actions and/or other sanctions if they fail to meet these obligations.

However, it is important for You to exercise caution to prevent unauthorized access to Your Personal Data. You are responsible for the confidentiality of Your password and information appearing on Your account. Consequently, You must ensure that You log out of Your session in the event of shared use of a computer.

**X. COOKIES**

The Site may use cookies or other technologies serving the same or similar purpose (together referred to as “cookies”), that may collect or store Personal Data. Cookies are text files stored and used to record Non-Personal and Personal Data concerning Your browsing and use of the Site. Cookies can be either persistent (i.e. remain after You logoff from the Site in order to be used on Your subsequent visits to the Site) or transient (i.e., removed when You close the web browser).

The table available at [http://faq.netvibes.com/knowledgebase/articles/1858438-cookies-we-use provides](http://faq.netvibes.com/knowledgebase/articles/1858438-cookies-we-use%20provides) You with the list of cookies Dassault Systèmes uses, their retention period and their purpose.

Dassault Systèmes uses cookies in order to:

  * improve Your user experience through, for example: 
    * enabling a service to recognize your device so You don't have to give the same information several times during one task;
    * recognizing that You may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do so for every web page requested;
  * analyze traffic and data on the Site to: 
    * measure how many people are using the Site, so the Site can be made easier to use and navigate and to make sure there is enough capacity to ensure the Site has adequate response times;
    * help Dassault Systèmes understand how users interact with the Site so Dassault Systèmes can improve its functionality and performance.

Dassault Systèmes may also use third party services (such as Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics, Piwik, DART, LinkedIn) to perform services on its behalf, in particular to:

  * analyze Your browsing habits and measure the Site audience,
  * analyze Your interests and offer You targeted marketing or advertising,
  * allow You to share content from the services with other people on social networks or to let these other people know what You are looking at or what You think (e.g., the “Like” button on Facebook),
  * analyze the effectiveness of the Site

In such a case, invisible pixels and cookies provided by such third party vendors may be used. By transmitting the information generated by these cookies, the cookies’ settings ensure that an IP address is anonymized before geo-localization and before storage. Our providers will use this information for the evaluation of Your use of the Site, compiling reports on the Site activity for Dassault Systèmes, to propose better services to You that are suited to Your needs, and display advertisements You that are suited to Your needs. Cookies will not associate Your IP address with any other data they hold.

When you browse the Site, cookies are enabled by default and data may be read from or stored locally on your device if your browser settings allow. You will be notified of the use of cookies the first time You access the Site with a device;  Dassault Systèmes will not install any cookies before obtaining your explicit consent. You may decide to accept or refuse some or all cookies. You can configure Your browser software to refuse all cookies (including cookies used for web analytics services); if You do so, however, some areas and features of the Site may not function properly and/or You may not be able to access some parts or services of the Site.

All browsers offer configuration options to:

  * inform You of the cookies saved on your computer;
  * allow You to accept or refuse them

You have the possibility to manage parameters and choose whether to accept certain cookies while on the Site. For more information, please read <http://faq.netvibes.com/knowledgebase/articles/1858441-how-to-turn-off-cookies>

**XI. Links to websites not controlled by Dassault Systèmes**

This Site might offer links to third party Websites that may be of interest to You.

Unless Dassault Systèmes receives Your express authorization, Dassault Systèmes does not share any Personal Data with these third parties. However, Dassault Systèmes may provide them with Non-Personal Data.

Dassault Systèmes does not exercise any control over the content of third party Websites or the practices of these third parties in connection with the protection of Personal Data that they might collect and are thus not under the control of Dassault Systèmes. Consequently, Dassault Systèmes declines all liability for the content of third party websites or the practices of these third parties concerning the protection of Personal Data.

It is therefore Your responsibility to inform yourself as to these third parties' privacy policies.

**XII. Dispute resolution**

Although Dassault Systèmes has put in place reasonable safeguards to protect Personal Data, Dassault Systèmes recognizes that there is no method of transmitting or storing Personal Data that is completely secure.

However, Dassault Systèmes is committed to ensure the privacy of Personal Data: if You have a reason to believe that the security of Your Personal Data has been compromised or misused, You should contact Dassault Systèmes by sending a request at <http://www.netvibes.com/en/contact-us>.

Dassault Systèmes will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints regarding use and disclosure of Personal Data in accordance with the principles contained in this Privacy Policy.

Unauthorized access to Personal Data or the improper use of Personal Data may constitute offenses under local law.

If Your usual place of residence is in European Union, Lichtenstein, Norway or Iceland, You have a right to file a complaint with Your competent data protection authority.

**XIII. Contact**

For any additional question concerning this Privacy Policy, to opt out of receiving information from Dassault Systèmes or any request regarding Your rights in Your Personal Data You may contact Dassault Systèmes by sending a request at <http://www..com/en/contact-us>.

Please note that you may also contact 3DS Data Protection Officer via the following address: [3DS.Compliance-Privacy@3ds.com](mailto:3DS.Compliance-Privacy@3ds.com).

**XIII. Date of entry into force of the privacy policy and changes to it**

This Privacy Policy may be updated according to Dassault Systèmes' requirements and circumstances, or where required by applicable laws and regulations so please check back periodically for updates.

If major changes occur to this Privacy Policy, Dassault Systèmes may inform you via email or via posting a notice on the Site.

  Last modification: October 21, 2019
